General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
- Davis, Richard Harding, 1864-1916, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Mr. Davidson, n.d. AM 15164
- Davis, Vernon M, 1910; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to David Murray, 24 November 1910. AM 15344
- Davis, Waters S, 1937-1939; 1 box (Box 13)
  Correspondence with European book dealers, 1937-1939. AM 17180
- Davison, Maria Rebecca, 1780-1858, 1834; 1 box (Box 13)
  ANS, 18 January 1834. AM 9964
- Davitt, Michael, 1846-1906, 1882; 1 box (Box 13)
  AMsS, poem, 14 July 1882. AM 83-50
- Dawes, Henry L. (Henry Laurens), 1816-1903, 1886-1887; 1 box (Box 13)
  3 ALsS and 1 LS to Edward L. Pierce, 28 October 1886 - 25 January 1887. AM 9680, 9681, 9682, and 9683
- Dawley, Lord, 1813; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to "Sir," 1813. AM 12984
- Dawson, John, 1809-1876; 1 box (Box 13)
  Correspondence of F. C. Brooke with John Picktord and others, 1809-1876; clippings of printed materials. AM 18068
- Day, Jeremiah, 1773-1867, 1826; 1 box (Box 13)
  ADS, recommendation of "Hudson River Seminary," 18 March 1826. AM 790
- Day, William Rufus, 1849-1923, 1899; 1 box (Box 13)
  TLS to Hamilton Holt, 25 October 1899. AM 18565
- Dayton, H, 1861; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Nelson W. Green concerning "Fifteen years with the Mormons," 14 February 1861. AM 9855
- De Berenger, 1827-1830; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to R. L. Perey asking to use his name as a reference, 5 October 1827; ALS to "My Dear Sir" arranging a call from Col. D'Arcy, 4 March 1830. AM 10679 and 10685
- De Blaguire, Lord, 1811; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to John Ridge, 13 April 1811. AM 12984
- De Pontiere, Louis, 1702; 1 box (Box 13)
  ADS, 29 October 1702. AM 22002
- De Vere, Aubrey Thomas, 1814-1902, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to "My Dear Sir," a publisher, n.d.
- Decatur, Stephen, 1779-1820, 1804; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Edward Preble form Malta asking for advance of 545 Spanish Dollars for the officers of the U.S. Schooner, 4 June 1804. AM 79-88
- Dehn, Adolf, 1895-1968, 1940; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Barke Doland, 26 February 1940. AM 13475
- Dehn, Georg, 1961; 1 box (Box 13)
  TLS to Professor von Kahler, 24 July 1961. AM 85-57
- Delahaye, Ernest, 1853-1930, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  7 drawings on 5 leaves of paper, of which 5 are reproduced in the book (Ex) PQ2464.xM3, n.d. AM 81-12
- Delisle, Leopold Victor, 1826-1910, 1906-1907; 1 box (Box 13)
  4 ALsS to Monsieur Badin in French, 26 October 1906 - 19 June 1907. AM 11035
- Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to "Dear Bax" (Arnold Bax) postponing a meeting, n.d. AM 87-39
- Dellenbaugh, Frederick Samuel, 1853-1935, 1934; 1 box (Box 13)
  TLS to "Stef." and photostat of same, 9 March 1934. AM 18464
- Dellenbaugh, Frederick Samuel, 1853-1935, 1928; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Ben Hamblin, with "Colorado Days," AMs poem, 13 September 1928. AM 19117
- Dello Joio, Norman, 1913-2008, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  AMs of music, "Lamb of God," n.d. AM 87-109
- Delvin, Lord, 1810; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to the 1st marquis of Westmeath, 26 April 1810. AM 12984
- Demarest, Maria Frelinghuysen, Letters to Jemima, 1867-1868; Demarest, Maria Frelinghuysen, 1841-1916; 1 folder (Box 13)
  Consists of three letters from Maria Frelinghuysen Demarest (1841-1916), a white New Jersey school teacher who worked during the Reconstruction era in Aiken, South Carolina, teaching both white children and Black formerly enslaved domestic workers. The return address on her letters is that of William J. Williams, Esq. of Aiken, who was likely her employer, and where she taught privately. The letters discuss teaching, as well as provide her comments on slavery, politics, and religious life in Aiken.
  Purchased from Ian Brabner in 2021 (AM 2022-020).
  Demarest
  Maria Frelinghuysen Demarest (1841-1916) was an educator from New Jersey. She and her sister Sarah Elizabeth Cornell Demarest operated a private school in Passaic, New Jersey, and she also taught privately in Aiken, South Carolina, during Reconstruction. She was the daughter of Reverend William Demarest (1813-1874), a Dutch Reformed clergyman and author.
  African Americans -- Education -- South Carolina -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Aiken (S.C.) -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- South Carolina -- Sources; Teachers -- South Carolina -- 19th century -- Correspondence; Women -- South Carolina -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Correspondence -- 19th century
- Dempster, John, 1827; 1 box (Box 13)
  ADS, 27 February 1827. AM 2004-128
- Denby, Edwin, 1870-1929, undated; 1 box (Box 13)
  Signature of Denby, Secretary of Navy, n.d. AM 12396
- Denney, James, 1856-1917, 1905-1965; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Miss Reith, 22 June 1905; TLS from David H. McAlpin, 23 November 1965; newspaper clipping. AM 18770
- Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928, 1886; 1 box (Box 13)
  ALS to Logan C. Murray, 22 April 1886. AM 10627
- Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928, 1925; 1 box (Box 13)
  TLS to George B. Lockwood, expressing gratitude for 3 issues of the National Republic, 19 August 1925. AM 87-39
- Derby, Edward George Geoffrey Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1799-1869, 1843; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS and typed copy to "Gentlemen," 29 July 1843. AM 19692
- Derby, Edward George Geoffrey Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1799-1869, 1853; 1 box (Box 14)
  L refusing to vote for M. Penton, n.d.; ALS to E. Humphrey, 3 May 1853; 2 engravings. AM 18565
- Derby, Edward George Geoffrey Smith Stanley, Earl of, 1826-1893, 1872; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to J. Browning concerning the vice presidency of the Society for the Encouragement of the Fine Arts, 25 January, 1872. AM 10955
- de Roos, W, 1826; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Lt. Col. The Earl of Oxbridge, 23 June 1826. AM 12984
- Desart, Lord, 1807; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to John O. Cuffe, 28 April 1807. AM 12984
- D'Estang, Charles Henri, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS and engraving. AM 2183
- Destutt de Tracy, Anoine Louis Claude, comte, 1754-1836, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  Signature on envelop addressed to L. B. Prince, n.d. AM 13238
- Devens, Charles, 1820-1891, 1880; 1 box (Box 14)
  L to Edward Pierce, 18 August 1880. AM 9684
- Devon, William Reginald Courtenay, Earl of, 1807-1888, 1835-1847; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "Dear Sir,"15 July 1835; ALS to the Editor of The Times, 10 July 1847. AM 12984
- Devonshire, William Cavendish, Duke of, 1720-1764, 1760; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Charles Townshend requesting payment for the "necessary woman," 1760; engraving. AM 18565
- Dewey, George, 1730; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Cyrus H. McCorkmick, 1730. AM 13365
- DeWitt, Wallace, Class of 1912, 1857-1915; 1 box (Box 57)
  19 by 25 in. DS, B.A. diploma, 1857; 2 U.S. passports, 1886 and 1915. AM 19289
- DeWitt, William R, 1835-1857; 1 box (Box 57)
  6 DsS, oversize diplomas, 1835-1857.
- Dicey, Edward, 1832-1911, 1863; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "Dear Fields," 16 May 1863. AM 87-24
- Dickey, James, 1923-1997, 1992; 1 box (Box 14)
  DS concerning the Cambridge/Bruccoli edition of The Great Gatsby, 15 January 1992. AM 92-82
- Dickey, James, 1923-1997, 1993; 1 box (Box 14)
  Exhibition brochure for the "Joseph M. Bruccoli Great War Collection" signed by James Dickey, 1993. AM 1996-94
- Dickey, James, 1923-1997, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  "On the Coosawattee," TMsS, poetry which appeared in Poetry magazine and Helmets, with inscription to William Luetge, 7 pp., n.d. AM 2004-103
- Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932, 1871; 1 box (Box 14)
  Autograph signature, 21 January 1871. AM 9942
- Dickinson, Roy, 1888-1976, 1923-1939; 1 box (Box 14)
  2 TLsS to S. M. Rising, 1 enclosing a catalog page for his book, The Ultimate Frog, 1923 and 1939. AM 14245
- Dickinson, D. S, 1853; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Dickinson recommending David S. Murray, 4 April 1853.
- Dickinson, Lavinia Norcross, 1833-1899, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  2 ALsS with envelopes, n.d. AM 18915
- Dickinson, Robert William, 1843; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Mr. Young Elfracombe, 4 pp., 10 December 1843. AM 13390
- Dickson, Sir Jeremiah, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to the Quarter Master General, n.d. AM 12984
- Dibdin, Thomas Frognall, 1776-1847, 1821; 1 box (Box 14)
  AM 16666
  ALS with copies, 1821; TMs, a retrospective note on Dibdin, n.d.; 3 engravings.
- Dibdin, Thomas Frognall, 1776-1847, Letter to James Millard, 1827 August 15; 1 box (Box 14)
  AM 2016-37
  A.L.s.; written from Newmarket.
  Also includes an undated handwritten copy.
- Dignum, Charles, 1765-1827, 1800; 1 box (Box 14)
  Theater ticket signed "C. D.," 4 June 1800. AM 9957
- Dilkes, W. Y, 1806; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Major Gen. Brownrigg, 15 May 1806. AM 12984
- Dilliard, Irving, 1904-2002, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  Pamphlet, "Advice to a Young Writer: Letters to Irving Dilliard," n.d. AM 1999-108
- Dillworth, Jonathan, and Hezekiah Hibbard, Carpenter's Account Books for Bush Hill Estate, 1771-1773; Dillworth, Jonathan; Hibbard, Hezekiah; 1 folder (Box B-001584, Folder 7)
  Consists of two account books kept by Quaker master builders Jonathan Dillworth and Hezekiah Hibbard detailing their carpentry work on several outbuildings that James Hamilton added to the Bush Hill Estate in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in the early 1770s. The account books are highly detailed, containing nearly 300 entries and including dimensions and costs for each feature of the coach house, stable, ice house, farm house, hay house, cart house, and cow house. Originally constructed in 1737, the Bush Hill Estate's mansion was briefly the home of John Adams during his term as vice president, and its outbuildings were later adapted for use as a fever hospital during the yellow fever epidemic of 1793. The estate remained within the Hamilton family until it was demolished in 1875.
  Purchased from Michael Brown Rare Books in 2021 (AM 2022-006).
  Philadelphia (Pa.) -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775 -- Sources.; Account books -- 18th century; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783; Bush Hill (Estate: Philadelphia, Pa.)
- Dilworth, William, 1837; 1 box (Box 14)
  ADS, statement of account to the estate of John D. Hart, 1 July 1837- 26 October 1837. AM 1762
- Dimmock, Charles, 1834; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Nathan P. Ames ordering a sword, 22 May 1834. AM 12716
- Dimond, W, 1808; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Mr. Capon about a pantomime, 2 pp., 22 April 1808. AM 9973
- Divine, Rev. M. J. (Father Divine), 1944; 1 box (Box 14)
  2 LsS to Robert Scott, 1 March 1944 and 22 March 1944. AM 13475
- Dix, Dorothea, Letter to Mr. Otto, 1865 October 5; Dix, Dorothea Lynde, 1802-1887; 1 folder (Box B-001555, Folder 11)
  Consists of a two-page letter from medical activist and reformer Dorothea Lynde Dix (1802-1887) to a Mr. Otto, in which Dix provides information to a father who was searching for his son, a wounded soldier who was missing in action following the Siege of Petersburg during the American Civil War. While Dix wrote her correspondence on letterhead of the Office of Women Nurses, United States Hospital Service, she had resigned from her position as Superintendent of the Army Nurses to the Union Army several months earlier, so the assistance she provided was conducted in a personal rather than official capacity.
  United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Medical care -- Sources; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Women -- Sources; Petersburg (Va.) -- History -- Siege, 1864-1865 -- Sources; Correspondence -- 19th century
- Dix, John A, 1914; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Miss Margaret Doane Gardiner, 4 February 1914; newspaper clipping of Dix. AM 12579
- Dobell, Sydney, 1824-1874, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Miss Symonds, n.d. AM 14918
- Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921, 1920; 1 box (Box 14)
  AMssS and TMss of "J. K. ob. 1820," 2 September 1920. AM 21566
- Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921, 1 box (Box 14)
  Printed advertisements for the Keats Memorial House Fund and the John Keats Memorial Volume, 1921. AM 21566
- Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921, 1920; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALsS to George Williamson concerning his contribution to the Keats Memorial Volume, 1920. AM 21566
- Doland, Parke, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Doland by unidentified person, n.d. AM 13475
- Dominicas, G, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS, unaddressed, recounting a story about electricity in the year 1776, n.d. AM 9585
- Dorrence, Russell, 1917; 1 box (Box 14)
  3 ALsS and 1 TLS to Howard S. Leach, recounting his experiences in army camps during WWI, 1917. AM 10554
- Doubleday, Russell, 1872-1849, 1917; 1 box (Box 14)
  TLS to T. B. Harned, 30 October 1917. AM 20678
- Douglas, James, 1816; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to the Quarter Master General, 21 August, 1816. AM 12984
- Douglas, Norman, 1868-1952, 1919-1923; 1 box (Box 14)
  3 ALsS (1919-1922) by Norman Douglas to his publisher, Martin Secker, 1 ALS (1923) by Douglas to "My dear Winifred." AM 2014-39
- Douglas, Olive Eleanor (Constance, Lady Alfred Douglas), undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Mr. Mathers, n.d. AM 17716
- Douglas, Stephen A. (Stephen Arnold), 1813-1861, 1833; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Hon. Robert McClelland, 14 March 1833. AM 20256
- Douglas, Stephen A. (Stephen Arnold), 1813-1861, 1851; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to E. C. West, 28 December 1851. AM 13365
- Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895, 1861 May 1-1885 April 15; 1 box
  AM 12182
  Purchased in October 1940.
  These items were separated from the Princeton University Library Collection on Slavery in the Americas (C1210), formerly known as the Miscellaneous Slavery Collection, during 2017 reprocessing.
  Douglass
  Frederick Douglass (1818-1895) was an African American abolitionist, social reformer, orator, writer, and statesman. After escaping from slavery in Maryland, he became one of the foremost leaders of the abolitionist movement in the United States, fighting to end slavery in the decades prior to the American Civil War. Douglass later served as an adviser to President Abraham Lincoln during the Civil War and fought for the adoption of constitutional amendments that guaranteed voting rights and other civil liberties for African Americans.
  African American abolitionists -- 19th century -- Correspondence.; Antislavery movements -- United States -- History -- 19th century -- Sources.; Harper's Ferry (W. Va.) -- History -- John Brown's Raid, 1859.
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895, Letter to William B. Sprague, 1861 May 1; 1 box (Box 14)
    One signed autograph letter (2 pages) from Frederick Douglass (1818-1895) in Rochester, New York, to William Buell Sprague (1795-1876) two weeks after the start of the American Civil War. The letter regards Sprague's discourse in commemoration of the late Supreme Court Justice John McLean (1785-1861) delivered on April 7, 1861, in the Second Presbyterian Church, Albany, which had mentioned Douglass. In the letter, Douglass describes his own life story, as well as his prediction that the abolition of slavery would be an outcome of the Civil War, writing, "For once the cause of the country has become the cause of the slave, and the difficulty of separating the one from the other, is a ground of hope that in the almost certain triumph of the country, the cause of justice and freedom to the bondman will triumph."
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895, Letter to Frank B. Sanborn, 1885 April 15; 1 box (Box 14)
    One signed autograph letter (3 pages) from Frederick Douglass (1818-1895) in Washington, D.C., to Frank B. (Franklin Benjamin) Sanborn (1831-1917) regarding the events leading up to the 1859 raid on Harper's Ferry, West Virginia, organized by abolitionist John Brown. In the letter, Douglass recounts meeting with Brown in Chambersburg, Pennsylvania, shortly before the raid; Brown's unsuccessful attempts to convince Douglass to support him; and the likelihood that a "Mr. Smith," probably referring to Gerrit Smith (1797-1874), knew the details of Brown's plan prior to the raid.
- Dowden, Edward, 1843-1913, 1896; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "My Dear Dixon," 11 November 1896; autograph, n.d. AM 17245
- Dowden, Edward, 1843-1913, 1896; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Mr. Pyne thanking him for his hospitality, 29 December 1896. AM 12211
- Dowden, Edward, 1843-1913, 1910; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "Dear Sir" quoting Measure for Measure, 20 April 1910. AM 90-13
- Dowers, Joseph, 1855; 1 box (Box 14)
  ANS to Thomas H. West promising Dowers will abstain from drinking, 8 February 1855. AM 80-9
- Downs, Olin, 1886-1955, 1943; 1 box (Box 14)
  TLS to Professor S. H. Weber, 30 April 1943. AM 12623
- Downe, Lord, 1787; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Mr. Leader, 18 April 1787. AM 12984
- Downing, A. J. (Andrew Jackson), 1815-1852, 1849-1851; 1 box (Box 14)
  7 ALsS and 7 ADsS to Luther Moker regarding settlement of law suit, 1849-1851. AM 13625
- Dowton, William, 1764-1851, 1804-1823; 1 box (Box 14)
  Theater ticket signed "W. D.," 17 May 1804; ADS, brief biographical statement, 11 June 1823. AM 9963
- Doyle, C. W. (Charles William), 1852-1903, 1872; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "Sir," 27 February 1872. AM 12984
- Drake, Francis, 1696-1771, 1868; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS from J. Read to G. C. Brooke concerning collections of Drake, 26 September 1868. AM 18920
- Draper, John William, 1811-1882, 1873; 1 box (Box 14)
  Photostat of ALS to Brig. General Atwood, 5 December 1873. AM 17484
- Draper, Mary Anna Palmer, 1839-1913, 1910; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to Edward Charles Pickering expressing gratitude for the photograph of the members of the Astronomical Society, 20 May 1910. AM 80-79
- Drayton, Percival, 1812-1865, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  Photostat of ALS to Capt. George Thom, n.d. AM 17484
- Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  AMS, poem "Nocturne," n.d. AM 1810
- Dripps, Robert Dunning, Class of 1898, 1897; 1 box (Box 14)
  Postcard from B. Percy to Dripps, 11 October 1897. AM 12823
- Driscoll, Emily, 1975; 1 box (Box 14)
  1 TLS to Doris Harris, 1 October 1975; 2 TLs (carbons) by Doris Harris about Adre De Coppet, 20 September and 8 October 1975. AM 2000-66
- Drum, Lavinia Morgan, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  Genealogical records of Evan Morgan, n.d. AM 18499
- Druz, Gustave, 1832-1895, 1871; 1 box (Box 14)
  ALS to "Mon Cher Boni," 1871.
- Dubois, Peter G, undated; 1 box (Box 14)
  AMs of autobiographical sketch, n.d. AM 15387
- Dudley, Charles R, 1899; 1 box (Box 14)
  TLS (copy) to Burton Society comparing their 1st volume of The Arabian Nights to the Benares edition, 3 July 1899. AM 22077
- Duell, Robert Holland, 1824-1891, 1862; 1 box (Box 15)
  Autograph on an envelope addressed to Mrs. Nelson W. Green, 3 May 1862. AM 9849
- Duer, Catherine 1755-1826, 1783; 1 box (Box 15)
  Photostat of ALS to her sister, 21 January 1783. AM 13021
- Duer, William 1747-1799, 1777; 1 box (Box 15)
  Photostat of ALS to Major General Wooster, 26 July 1777. AM 17484
- Dumas, Alexandre, fils, 1824-1895, undated; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to unknown female correspondent and typed copy of same, n.d. AM 15900
- Dumas, Mathieu, comte, 1753-1837, 1778; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to Le Chevalier Grand, La Haye, introducing Samuel Witham Stockton, 27 May 1778. AM 22002
- Dunbar, Field, 1828-1854, 1914-1915; 1 box (Box 15)
  Biographical material, including: TMs and D with handwritten notes, 13 February 1915 and 21 December 1914; ALS to Miss Buhler from unknown sender, n.d. AM 14006
- Duncan, John, 1809; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to "Dear Sir," 1 February 1809. AM 12984
- Duncan, Maria Rebecca (Davison), 1780-1858, 1808; 1 box (Box 15)
  Theater ticket signed "M. R. D.," 1808. AM 9969
- Duncannon, Lord, 1839; 1 box (Box 15)
  Photostat and typewritten copy of ALS to Duchess of Kent on the advisability of a public appearance with her daughter, Queen Victoria, 4 March 1839. AM 11830
- Dundas, Davis, 1792; 1 box (Box 15)
  ADS, receipt, 26 July 1792. AM 12984
- Dundas, M, undated; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to unknown recipient, n.d. AM 12984
- Dunlop, William Laird, Class of 1852, 1901; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to Henry Clay Cameron inviting him to visit, 20 February 1901. AM 8462
- Dundin, Aleyn, Bishop of Durham, 1946; 1 box (Box 15)
  AMsS, article on supply of books in England, 3 pp., March 1946; ALS from P. D. Bailey, forwarding the article, 12 March 1946. AM 13197
- Dunmore, John Murray, Earl of, 1732-1809, 1773; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to "Dear Sir," 19 October 1773. AM 13366
- Dunsany, Edward John Moreton Drax Plunkett, Baron, 1878-1957, undated; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to Miss Nod, n.d. AM 18117
- Durant, Thomas J. (Thomas Jefferson), 1817-1882, 1852; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to Jefferson Davis urging the appointment of Miles Taylor to Justice of the Supreme Court, 2 pp., 30 December 1852. AM 8703
- Durant, Will, 1885-1981, 1929-1934; 1 box (Box 15)
  TLS to Miss Bramble regarding his talk "Is Man a Machine," 5 March 1929; TLS to Mr. Manson concerning Durant's "The Story of Philosophy," 5 July 1934. AM 87-24
- Durfé, Claude, 1546; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS in French to the Spanish Ambassador, September 1546. AM 92-87
- Durrell, Lawrence, 1912-1990, 1974; 1 box (Box 15)
  TN and TNS to Mr. Vrettos regarding the recipient's book, 10 June and 4 July 1974. AM 2004-103
- Duryee, John, 1812; 1 box (Box 15)
  DS, receipt signed by John, William, and Simon Duryee, 1812. AM 2225
- Dussaux, Jean, 1913; 1 box (Box 15)
  Identification book of French soldier Dussaux, 1913. AM 22077
- Duval, Gabriel, 1752-1844, 1781-1826; 1 box (Box 15)
  3 DsS, receipts and drafts, 1781-1790; DS, inspection by Supreme Court, 1826; ALS, unaddressed, 1812; ALS to General Dearborn, 1811; 2 engravings. AM 18565
- Duyckinck, Evert A. (Evert Augustus), 1816-1878, 1872; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to J. H. Morrell, 22 July 1872. AM 9961
- Dwight, Sereno Edwards, 1786-1850, 1826; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS, unaddressed, testifying for David Marsh Smith, 3 March 1826. AM 8532
- Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817, 1811; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS, unaddressed, testifying for David Marsh Smith, 28 October 1811. AM 8531
- Dyer, Thomas E, 1808; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to the Quarter Master General, 6 September 1808. AM 12984
- Dyott, William, 1808-1809; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to "My Dear Sir," 1809; 2 ALsS to Alexander Bruce, July 1808 and 20 July 1809. AM 12984
- Eakin, Samuel, Rev., 1745-1784, undated; 1 box (Box 15)
  Extract from R. G. Johnson's "History of Salem, NJ" about the Rev. Samuel Eakin, Ms, n.d. AM 88-77
- Eames, Wilberforce, 1855-1937, 1905; 1 box (Box 15)
  TLS to Richard D. Fisher, 23 March 1905. AM 22077
- Earwaker, John Parsons, 1847-1895, 1890; 1 box (Box 15)
  Misc. notes, letters, and other material found in "The History of the Ancient Parish of Sandbach, Co. Chester," 1890. AM 77-128
- Eastman, Max, 1883-1969, 1938; 1 box (Box 15)
  TLS to Miss Ruth Mauersberger which mentions Albert Einstein, 17 May 1938; ALS by Mauersberger mentioning Eastman, n.d. AM 1996-104
- Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842, 1828; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to "Dear Sir" concerning a book on geology, 1 August 1828. AM 1941
- Eaton, Charlotte Ann (Waldie), Mrs., 1788-1859, 1821; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to G. Molini, 19 August 1821. AM 20531
- Eaton, William H., 1764-1811, 1801; 1 box (Box 15)
  ADS concerning a ship, 5 January 1801. AM 82-81
- Ebbinghaus, Herman, 1850-1909, 1906-1909; 1 box (Box 15)
  Postcard to G. von Allesch, 12 December 1906; postcard to H. S. Langfeld, 2 February 1909. AM 79-135
- Eccles, Mary Hyde, Letters, 1995 August-September; 1 box (Box 15)
  AM 2017-29
  4 letters from Mary Morley Crapo Hyde Eccles, Viscountess Eccles (1912-2003) at Four Oaks Farm to Charles E. Greene and N. John Hall regarding manuscripts.
- Echard, Laurence, 1670-1730, 1720; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to "Dear Sir" offering a copy of his History of England, 6 January 1720. AM 17786
- Eckley, Joseph, 1750-1811, 1796; 1 box (Box 15)
  ALS to Joshua Wentworth regarding the value of land in Portsmouth, 9 September 1796. AM 2008-111
- Edgeworth, Maria, Fragment of Autograph Manuscript of 'Helen', circa 1833; Edgeworth, Maria, 1768-1849; 1 folder (Box B-001748, Folder 1)